hi and welcome to living in Central Texas I'm\h
Aundrea Dudik realtor with Vista Real Estate\h\h
and I'm here with my right-hand guy an expert in\h
lending Jacob Studdard with Edge Home Financing\h\h
fantastic it's a pleasure being here Aundrea I\h
appreciate it I I look forward to helping out some\h\h
future home buyers and getting their questions\h
answered awesome so you're curious about the\h\h
first steps in buying a home well stay tuned we're\h
going to cover it all so before we get started I\h\h
think it'd be good to maybe discuss how Jacob and\h
I met because um relationships are everything in\h\h
real estate there are a lot of parties involved\h
when buying or selling a home and I don't even\h\h
know that people realize how many people are\h
involved um but the relationships that you have\h\h
can really help guide a successful transaction and\h
make you know make the difference between a really\h\h
positive home buying experience and a not so great\h
one absolutely there's there's so many different\h\h
players that are involved in just a standard\h
transaction it's great to have a little bit\h\h
of transparency and insight on what it actually\h
takes from a behind the scenes perspective that\h\h
way you understand there's a lot of moving parts\h
and how important communication is between all\h\h
parties to ensure a smooth home body process so\h
if you think about it so if you think about it\h\h
when you're purchasing a home there's going to\h
be buyer agent sellers agent lenders um we've\h\h
got title companies all the people involved with\h
title um you got appraisal survey yes appraisers\h\h
surveyor home homeowners insurance homeowners\h
insurance home inspectors yep I the actual buyers\h\h
and the actual sellers yeah there's there's a lot\h
of moving parts so you put all those together it\h\h
it makes sense for everyone to kind of be on the\h
same page which is the importance of communication\h\h
between each party because there's so many moving\h
Parts if one person's on a different page or it's\h\h
late or is it tracking something that others\h
should be then that's when mistakes happen or\h\h
the ball gets dropped and yep yep and so that's\h
how Jacob and I actually started working together\h\h
so I've been in real estate for I think about 7\h
years now and you've been in this how long now\h\h
Jacob 3 years three years yep so one day I was\h
just driving and Jacob kind of coold called me\h\h
and introduced himself good old coold call which\h
normally doesn't work and I mean I get a lot of\h\h
phone calls but it was the way he carried himself\h
in the conversation it was very low pressure it\h\h
was kind and I just I could immediately pick up on\h
the fact that you were a good communicator and so\h\h
he asked me for um to Coffee to kind of discuss\h
the products and services that he offered and we\h\h
met and we just really hit it off reaching out\h
to uh Aundrea was definitely uh a big move um\h\h
she's a great producer fantastic agent um you can\h
tell by just her Communication in her um post on\h\h
her social media that it was somebody who I\h
wanted to work with M um and so from that I\h\h
knew that building a relationship with an agent\h
who actually embodies selfless service is going\h\h
to be something that will help all of us you know\h
serve um home buyers out there and make sure that\h\h
they're usted in good hands so oh thank you that's\h
so kind so we met up for coffee and he was talking\h\h
about the different Services he offered and well\h
first we we connected because we both have two\h\h
young daughters and so you know that's helpful in\h
a lot of different way we both experienced a lot\h\h
of similar but different things exactly but I had\h
um I think there are a lot of misconceptions with\h\h
mortgage brokers and one of my biggest things as a\h
realtor is a fear of not having a local lender so\h\h
a good agent's going to tell you hey we recommend\h
that you work with a local lender and reason being\h\h
well there's a lot of different reasons but local\h
lender um they they know our Market they know the\h\h
people that work here other people that they'll\h
be communicating with um they know our property\h\h
taxes which is a big one um what what s anyway\h
they just they just know things better and so I\h\h
get Leary with mortgage brokers sometimes because\h
they're not always local um and I just haven't had\h\h
great experiences um but when Jacob was really\h
talking about the different Services he offered\h\h
it was it was a different experience um overall\h
because I could actually have that face to face\h\h
Bas conversation with them and very quickly I\h
realized that the communication was not going\h\h
to be an issue for sure yeah so um that is that\h
is a big thing there's there's a difference out\h\h
there between all the different types of lenders\h
all right so there's your mortgage brokers your\h\h
retail lenders and just your standard Banks um\h
so each each entity has their own pros and cons\h\h
to working with them they all have their own uh\h
[\h__\h] Mish hats so I guess Jacob what were some\h\h
of the things that you you felt like in that\h
moment or what are some things that you feel\h\h
that as a mortgage broker you can offer that\h
maybe a typical lender couldn't the advantage\h\h
of working with the mortgage broker we have\h
here at atal Finance others are different but\h\h
in general the sense is the same that we have\h
here over 140 different wholesale lenders that\h\h
we're partnered with which means a different set\h
of options a different set of overlays and each\h\h
lender has their own like their expert fields of\h
of different type of loans that they work on so we\h\h
have a lot more um options options when it comes\h
to fitting our buyers into a certain area um when\h\h
it to ensure that they're served in the best way\h
possible rather than having One Stop Shop of if\h\h
you can't get it through here then you're done\h
and you have to move on and find somewhere else\h\h
versus US you have the ability to shop around we\h
can do the shopping for you um which makes the not\h\h
only just the experience much more seamless\h
it also ensures that agents have a lot more\h\h
opportunity in us as well for closings to offer\h
the ability to buy more homes and get more people\h\h
in the house yeah so basically one of the one of\h
the biggest things was every buyer is unique and\h\h
every buyer's situation is unique and so yes there\h
are different um there's everyone has different\h\h
situations are they self-employed how long have\h
they been employed what's their credit like\h\h
what's their de to income like uh what's their\h
what's their overall employment status well the\h\h
thing with Jacob is that he can instead of just\h
having one set of parameters to work in is what\h\h
he's saying I can call him and he'll he can reach\h
out to 10 different exactly people and say based\h\h
off of their situation this one will work best and\h
so you might just get to know from another lender\h\h
because they don't have that flexibility but he's\h
able to kind of shop around and help figure figure\h\h
that out okay that's great way to put it yeah so\h
flexibility is is the number one bonus that comes\h\h
with working with the mortgage broker and you said\h
it perfectly there each buyer is so unique in in\h\h
just their situation and there's there's what's\h
called overlays right so overlays just to give you\h\h
kind of a background of what that means there's\h
the existing load L guidelines that all lenders\h\h
regardless of status they have to abide by now\h
that's the raw loan guidelines for conventional\h\h
Fanny May Freddy Max your FHA VA USDA LS now um\h
what overlays are is additional set of rules that\h\h
the lenders themselves actually set to kind of\h
narrow and filter in the type of loans that they\h\h
want now that can mean a Max de the income ratio\h
that can mean a minimum credit score that can mean\h\h
um loads of different things down payment Etc so\h
so there's so overall there's every loan type has\h\h
their own set of guidelines that are immovable\h
or required based off regardless of the lender\h\h
but then the lender can also have their set of\h
requirements which are different for each lender\h\h
and yours are more flexible ex exactly and having\h
that having that amount of lenders that we're\h\h
partnered with and it being on the wholesale side\h
the amount of overlays were a lot less prevalent\h\h
and it allows for more buyers to purchase homes\h
and it allows for a lot more flexibility yeah so\h\h
I I've come to Jacob I mean in full transparency\h
I think we've been working together about a year\h\h
now and the reason I go to is the number one\h
reason is the communication because if I don't\h\h
hear from him immediately I know I will I'll get a\h
message or something I can't get to you right now\h\h
I'll get back to you shortly and um no one's ever\h
in the dark at at any point everyone knows what's\h\h
going on and in my opinion everything is really\h
figureoutable and we can figure anything out and\h\h
especially when you have a dozen people involved\h
in the in the process a lot of those are out of\h\h
our control and I think that we get that but in\h
order to figure it out we have to work together\h\h
as a team and um that communication is there so\h
there have been quite a few circumstances already\h\h
where other buyers of mine have been um rejected\h
or denied by other lenders based off of certain\h\h
circumstances and I've been able to call Jacob and\h
say hey this is their situation and not only the\h\h
good news is is we were kind of talking about\h
this before the video started there different\h\h
not everyone's in it for the same reason and of\h
course we're here to support our families too\h\h
and like we have to make an income as well but I\h
think you can tell when you work with us that we\h\h
genuinely do care about making a good experience\h
for the person that we're working with and doing\h\h
a really good job and um you know Jacob is very\h
good at even if it's not a right now thing like\h\h
doing a what do you call it credit repair or\h
yeah basically kind of like building a game\h\h
plan um so not every buyer is ready right away\h
right so that's another thing is just because\h\h
you're not ready now doesn't mean you won't be\h
ready in the future and so it's important to\h\h
get with somebody who will will invest in you as a\h
individual or as a family so that you can actually\h\h
build some sort of game plan y that allows you\h
to kind of backwards plan from a point of what\h\h
you want to buy and understand what it's going\h
to take to get there that way at least when you\h\h
get closer to that end goal home owning you're\h
in a much better position than you were in the\h\h
beginning if you were to just kind of jump in not\h
really knowing where you're at and maybe you need\h\h
a little work and that's kind of the thing too is\h
if you're willing to invest in not just yourself\h\h
but also your business and others they it's one of\h
those things where it comes down to a personality\h\h
difference is we actually want to selflessly\h
serve our clients rather than just pushing people\h\h
through volume wise just to to cash a check it's\h
not like that agreed um and you know another thing\h\h
is too is in when you work closely with someone\h
when it's a good team effort you're able to catch\h\h
things and communicate well what what another good\h
example is recently had someone that was referred\h\h
to me and she was really emotionally ready to buy\h
but when I started talking to her about her down\h\h
payment and her closing costs which we'll go over\h
that in just a second here she was new you know\h\h
she didn't understand the whole process and what\h
could be covered by someone else what had to be\h\h
covered by her what those costs look like and and\h
she really didn't have any cash to do it and um\h\h
when we started having that conversation I could\h
tell she was discouraged and started thinking and\h\h
I said well do you have any retirement accounts\h
and she said yes I said do you have a 401k or\h\h
anything like that and she said yes and of course\h
like I know my Lane like there's there's only so\h\h
many qualifying questions I could ask but that's\h
that gives me um a good place to say like hey now\h\h
that we know what you're looking for and what\h
you're what you are are hoping to do we need to\h\h
get you over to someone that's going to really\h
be able to look at your full situation get you\h\h
pre-qualified dig into your file look at all those\h
little pieces and see what amount you qualify for\h\h
and what your options even are and so I I gave her\h
Jacob's information along with a couple others and\h\h
said um called Jacob and I said here's this is who\h
will probably be calling you this is her situation\h\h
here's what I'm thinking so we're already tracking\h
on the same page and the client kind of isn't\h\h
having to go through I mean she of course she\h
can but she doesn't have to go through in detail\h\h
or forget if she missed anything we've had that\h
conversation and I think that that's comforting\h\h
for them too is to know that there's already\h
people working for exactly yeah and and to to your\h\h
credit it's as a lender and a loan officer on my\h
side of things it is great when an agent actually\h\h
does some of the pre-screening for you um because\h
not only does it help the the client understand\h\h
that the agent is going to be asking some of this\h
ourselves as a lender is going to ask just it's\h\h
typical preening pre-screening as in like income\h
assets all those fun things so you do a great job\h\h
on that and I do appreciate it it's kind of the\h
standard that most agents should start to kind\h\h
of adopt is is a good amount of pre-screening\h
questions so but when that communication is\h\h
there I mean we're able to kind of fill in the\h
gaps for each other or like catch things that\h\h
maybe the other person didn't and anyway so that's\h
yeah so and to her point with all those questions\h\h
and I'm going to read ering some of those same\h
questions so I have the same understanding as\h\h
she has um from from the lender's point of view\h
so after having that conversation with the buyer\h\h
and getting all those details in place what I'm\h
able to do is in backwards plan from her end dat\h\h
of when she wants to buy a house so I know what\h
steps we need to take to get there um at the end\h\h
of the day or at the end of that conversation she\h
was super happy she she never thought she'd be\h\h
able to buy a house and after listening to her\h
and understanding where she's at now she she's\h\h
actioning her game plan all way through she's\h
very happy yeah it makes it makes the difference\h\h
like it to to really just have give people the\h
time and have those conversations can go along\h\h
ways yeah so I guess we'll get into what are some\h
frequently asked questions and um it it what are\h\h
some frequently asked questions in purchasing of\h
home question number one how much money do I need\h\h
to purchase a home all right yeah so for down pay\h
is going to be the number one so down payment is\h\h
essentially the money you're putting towards the\h
principal on day on the day of closing in in most\h\h
cases if you're looking to buy a $400,000 home\h
you can put anywhere from 3 to 5% down depending\h\h
on the Lan type sometimes zero in that case\h
but down payment is going to be the first um\h\h
item that we're looking at and down payments a\h
non-negotiable it's basically skin in the game\h\h
for the lender it shows the lender that you're a\h
serious buyer because if you default on the loan\h\h
or you back out they need they're going to have to\h
kind of recoup that right exactly yeah so the down\h\h
payment does show skin in the gain um and on a\h
$400,000 loan you're looking at $12,000 to $20,000\h\h
down um now you depending on the loan program you\h
can adjust that to each you know each scenario is\h\h
unique obviously but in general that's what what\h
you're going to be looking to bring to to the\h\h
table on a home price of that range unless you are\h
a VA buyer right unless you're a VA buyer then you\h\h
have the option to do a 0% down so long you have\h
been entitled it to do so which is fantastic so\h\h
in every home purchasing situation you're going to\h
have down payment and closing costs down payment\h\h
is non-negotiable no one can pay for that other\h
than the buyer um but again VA loan they they're\h\h
they have the option on VA loan to put to bring\h
money to the table in regards to down payment\h\h
if they want okay and then closing cost so closing\h
cost that's a little bit different yeah so closing\h\h
costs are a lot different um and there's basically\h
what closing cost are it's the cost of all the\h\h
third parties that we mentioned earlier that are\h
involved in the home buying process so there's\h\h
there's a handful of them so not to mention all of\h
them but just some some general ones is your title\h\h
fees your prepaid interest which is remaining\h
days in that month that you owe insurance for\h\h
which you close you have your prepaid homeowners\h
insurance which is basically the First full year\h\h
of your homeowners insurance premium that's due\h
on closing you have your property taxes you have\h\h
ES grow um appraisal fees those are pretty much\h
the the bulk of it there's other fees in there\h\h
uh but in general those are the fees you'll have\h
um for closing costs and so closing costs will\h\h
process-wise how how this will go is you get\h
pre-qualified you speak with you either you\h\h
can speak with I think you have two different\h
ways that you can go you can either speak with\h\h
an agent first so that we can decide you know\h
we can do another video on this at a later time\h\h
but are you purchasing a new home versus a resale\h
home what are your goals cuz sometimes your goals\h\h
will determine financing are you looking to do a\h
new construction home where you're you're doing\h\h
a custom home where you're carrying the note where\h
you that's going to look a little bit different so\h\h
you can speak with a a realtor first or you can\h
speak with a lender first I don't really think\h\h
there's a right or a wrong way in going about\h
that and then once you speak with your lender\h\h
speak with Jacob um he'll help you fill out an\h
application get pre-qualified and then we'll\h\h
know how much money um once you're once you're\h
pre-approved m how much house you can afford and\h\h
at that point we can start the fun part of buying\h
a home exactly um but what happens is once we know\h\h
that amount we start our we have our conversation\h
we can start our home search and then if you find\h\h
a home that you're really interested in I think a\h
good realtor is going to get in contact with the\h\h
lender and say because we want to make sure we're\h
we're doing we're using our negotiation power to\h\h
its full advantage and so what one of the best\h
ways to do that for example is I'll call Jacob to\h\h
say hi I'm I'm hey I'm working with Jane Doe and\h
she is interested in purchasing 1234 Main Street\h\h
this is the offer price she's looking to close\h
in 30 days um can you give us estimated closing\h\h
costs down payment and um monthly payment really\h
as you get through the process and you get closer\h\h
to that pre-approval or at that pre-approval one\h
of the good things is is we're able to especially\h\h
with Aundrea cuz she'll communicate and let me\h
know like going to go view a home and if the\h\h
buyer's super interested in that home she'll\h
I'll ask for the address and what we're able\h\h
to do is we're able to tailor that application to\h
that address so we can get a pretty good ballpark\h\h
estimate of what the estimated closing costs will\h
be along with monthly payment and all that good\h\h
stuff and this is another lender because I can't\h
tell you the amount of times that of course people\h\h
want to go look at they want to look at homes on\h
weekends and now we're on a Saturday or Sunday and\h\h
I can't get a hold of a lender to some of these\h
questions um another big reason to work with a\h\h
local blender but I appreciate that yes so Jacob\h
gives closing costs right so then at that point\h\h
I'm able to have a conversation with you as the\h
buyer and say all right let's submit our offer\h\h
how much because we can ask for the seller to pay\h
towards your closing cost well at this current\h\h
moment we are in a fabulous buyer market for sure\h
and so you know we've seen some of the most killer\h\h
deals for our buyers right absolutely Testament\h
to you yeah they're both them but at that point\h\h
you know if houses have been sitting for 6 months\h
if Jacob tells me yeah they're closing costs are\h\h
$88,000 but if you can buy if you can get x amount\h
um in additional credits from the seller sorry and\h\h
concessions from the seller then we can buy down\h
their rate a little bit so everyone's freaking out\h\h
about a 7% interest rate but in this market we can\h
you know what if we can get all your closing costs\h\h
paid for and we can get the seller to pay down\h
your rate and so at the end of the day you're\h\h
getting the home that you love you're not coming\h
very much out of pocket maybe just your down\h\h
payment and you get a lower interest rate I mean\h
again of course every situation is different but\h\h
we are able to do that a lot right now exactly yes\h
so that's one of the big the big bonuses in the\h\h
market right now is it's definitely a buyer Market\h
there's a lot of room for negotiation and if you\h\h
paare with the great agent you'll find that and\h
in from my side nearly all of the contracts that\h\h
I've gotten especially with Aundrea have some\h
sort of closing cost involved so or excuse me\h\h
seller credit involved so the seller is basically\h
conceeding an x amount of dollars to cover the\h\h
buyer's closing cost and their down and their um\h
discount points to purchase down their rate so\h\h
rather than having to come out of your own pocket\h
to pay for a rate buy down for example and you can\h\h
negotiate to have the seller cover that for you\h
yeah um obviously each scenario is different and\h\h
each buyer is unique but at the end of the day to\h
offset the increase in rates just in the overall\h\h
Market that's a very very creative tool to use\h
that only the market right now is offering is\h\h
the seller credits to buy that down for you yes\h
so to Circle back and to summarize on that so\h\h
how much money every loan type is different the\h
loan types that we're typically going to look at\h\h
VA FHA conventional USDA would be on there U if\h
you're a USDA buyer you're pretty unique and S\h\h
so yes so each of those is a little bit different\h
in the amounts that you either that in the amounts\h\h
that you have to put down in terms of your\h
down payment but I think Jacob gave a pretty\h\h
good range of that and then closing costs your\h
closing costs can vary based off of time of year\h\h
but what would you say right now range of closing\h
cost yeah so typically 2 to 3% of the sales price\h\h
in just closing cost that cloting down payment is\h
is a really good ballpark estimate obviously for\h\h
Budget try to plan for the latter end of that\h
just so you you know can pre can be prepared\h\h
depending on property taxes homeowners insurance\h
those are so adjustable right now um especially\h\h
with the increase and homeowners insurance is um\h
it's good to kind of offset that expectation but\h\h
if you have any concerns about that give Jacob\h
a call so that he can look at your particular\h\h
situation and find what's best for you because\h
sometimes it's not always best I mean right we\h\h
had a we had a buyer not too long ago where\h
she did have some money saved in savings but\h\h
she was excited about a down payment assistance\h
program but it was going to end up costing her a\h\h
lot more money each month by using that than if\h
she were to use her saing but Jacob was able to\h\h
go through all of that in great detail to explore\h
what situation was best for her so again there's\h\h
lots of options you can explore that with him\h
that's our that's our first question question\h\h
number two what is the first step in buying a home\h
we kind of went over this one a little bit earlier\h\h
but first step would be to just pick up the phone\h
and make a call um raage out to EO Jacob myself\h\h
and you know have that conversation and we'll\h
help guide you our job is to make it as easy and\h\h
honestly enjoyable as possible buying a home\h
should truthfully not be stressful it should\h\h
be exciting and we're here to kind of carry that\h
burden and make things easier for you so call us\h\h
and we will be able to guide you on your next\h
steps get you into filling out an application\h\h
finding out how much home you can afford and then\h
start looking at homes and then everything else\h\h
will hold your will hold your hand through rat\h
we'll hold your hand AB we all hold your hand\h\h
through Home Inspections negotiations of repairs\h
um you know getting everything all the little\h\h
goodies in your contract and then making sure\h
we'll both ensure that everything from once you're\h\h
under contract to closing is extra absolutely so I\h
I would definitely say one if if you're looking to\h\h
purchase is easy to get kind of that shiny object\h
syndr and want to look at all types of Homes at\h\h
all different R uh you know P purchase prices\h
and and listing the mouses it's very easy to get\h\h
caught in that rabbit hole so I would definitely\h
recommend to try to get pre-approved or at least\h\h
pre-qualified in general before you really start\h
shopping around that way you can set a realistic\h\h
shopping window for yourself and for your agents\h
well we don't want to have you heartbroken if\h\h
you find the home of your drinks but it turns out\h
you're pre-qualified yes you're you can't afford\h\h
it and you're you can afford $220,000 or $50,000\h
less well now your eyes are kind of set on a whole\h\h
nets worth a lot more and alternatively maybe you\h
can afford a lot more that you didn't even realize\h\h
and now you've limited yourself because you didn't\h
have that call up front and maybe even miss the\h\h
home that you really want there's plenty of\h
examples of of both of those right there's plenty\h\h
of examples of buyers getting over zealous and\h
wanting to look in a Range that they realistically\h\h
um cannot afford versus the opposite where they\h
thought they were kind of limiting themselves\h\h
as to what they thought they could afford um\h
but when it came down to it they were actually\h\h
able to afford much more than they could have\h
ever imagined so it's definitely important to\h\h
get yourself pre-approved which would be the best\h
thing um to set that expectation for all parties\h\h
um so we don't have any broken hearts at no broken\h
heart exactly no broken heart wor not a good\h\h
conversation no question number three what credit\h
do I need in order to purchase the home yeah so\h\h
there's a lot of misconceptions out there with\h
with credit scores right so going back to overlays\h\h
each lender can technically set their own minimum\h
credit score requirements for each loan type um\h\h
in general it's going to depend on which loan\h
type fits your scenario okay so that's number\h\h
one for specific credit scores it depends on\h
loan type right so in general conventional\h\h
loans you're looking at somewhere around a 620\h
okay that's just the minimum requirements for\h\h
FHA you can go down to 580 with the minimum down\h
payment as you go down further your down payment\h\h
may or may not increase just for um qualification\h
requirements now VA loans there's technically no\h\h
credit score um but obviously I don't recommend\h
trying to buy if you don't have a decent credit\h\h
score likely in the 600s just to set yourself\h
up in in the best position possible so Jacob\h\h
what happens if someone has no credit like if\h
someone say for example I had a client who said\h\h
I'm doing the da Dave Ramy method it's not that\h
we have bad credit we actually have no credit\h\h
what happens then yeah so there is what's\h
called non-traditional credit so you can\h\h
actually purchase a home with no credit scores now\h
there's different requirements to it obviously but\h\h
technically what you can look at is your previous\h
rental history if you have made any lease payments\h\h
or um like if you're leasing an apartment or\h
house um you can use those to support that you\h\h
actually make your payments on time other things\h
are utilities electric bills phone bills so if\h\h
you have a combination of those you can you can\h
actually have the opportunity to buy house just\h\h
with that supporting yourself awesome yeah pretty\h
neat yep question number four where Jacob and I\h\h
currently are we're in Bell County Y and we are\h
very close to Fort cabaza formerly Fort Hood\h\h
and so we get a lot of Veteran buyers and Jacob\h
himself is a veteran Army veteran yes ma'am um Hy\h\h
um artillery Air Defense Artillery close y you're\h
you're pretty close thank you and so um we serve a\h\h
lot of veterans here and a lot of times they're\h
they're they're pcsing here they're coming here\h\h
they're not there's just this extra almost element\h
of trust that I think goes into working with them\h\h
because they're not here um and so we get a lot\h
of va questions and a lot of va misconception\h\h
can you use your VA loan more than once yes so\h
absolutely you can use it more than once so you\h\h
have what's called your Certificate of Eligibility\h
which proves your eligibility for the VA loan in\h\h
there there's what's called your entitlement so\h
as long as you have remaining entitlement from\h\h
your first purchase you can technically purchase\h
a home again using your VA loan and keeping your\h\h
first purchase open so long you qualify for both\h
mortgage payments it's not very common but it's a\h\h
thing that people don't know about it no and so\h
I had a a really young couple reach out to me a\h\h
few months ago and they said they were interested\h
in buying a home and they were wanting to go um\h\h
they were they were looking into an FHA loan first\h
time going buyer loan and I said but wait didn't\h\h
you say that your husband works at Fort kazus\h
and you know it's stationed at Fort kazus and\h\h
she said well yes and I said so he's not using his\h
VA she said well we don't want to use it just yet\h\h
we want to save that for our forever home and it\h
just I was so glad that I'd been paying attention\h\h
and that we'd had that conversation and I said no\h
we're going to save you a lot of money right now\h\h
and you are going to just be so happy about this\h
and yeah another one of the um huge misconceptions\h\h
is that selling your house or um rolling closing\h
cost into the loan are too too big things so one\h\h
you you can't really roll the closing cost in on\h
a VA loan purchase on a refinance that's different\h\h
you can do that and then also on the selling\h
part once you sell your home if you purchase\h\h
it with the VA you can technically free up that\h
entitlement that you previously used to purchase\h\h
at home using your VA so it's it's something that\h
educating and talking through with with people who\h\h
actually do a lot of VA loan transactions will\h
know um just based off the guidelines so cool\h\h
something pretty neat yeah so if you have any\h
questions about um purchasing or using your VA\h\h
entitlement Jacob's just a great resource on that\h
I am pretty Limited in in My overall knowledge of\h\h
that cuz there's a lot of nuances or little pieces\h
expert like total expert on that I appreciate that\h\h
we we do our best something that we actually we\h
care near and dear about um you know actually\h\h
serving our veterans to the utmost potential that\h
that we're allowed to do um and educating is one\h\h
of the main things that that we're really here\h
for so yeah St back you well we hope you enjoyed\h\h
this video on frequently asked questions in the\h
home buying process there are a lot of things\h\h
to cover if you have any questions or want to\h
contact either one of us contact information\h\h
is below in the details and don't forget to watch\h
my most recent video on the difference between um\h\h
general home inspection and a VA inspection\h
AKA VA appraisal until next time thanks